

604-721-0066 dakota@dakotamauza.com Vancouver, BC

Github: DakotaPaige Portfolio: <u>dakotamauza.com</u>

Summary

I am a full stack developer with a focus on the front-end. I have over 3 years of experience building apps with React.js and always enjoy a new development challenge. I have strong organization and communication skills, and am able to work well both individually and with a team.

Experience

BAM DIGITAL

INTERMEDIATE FRONT END DEVELOPER – MARCH 2020 - CURRENT JUNIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER – SEPTEMBER 2018 - MARCH 2020

Working both independently and on a development team to create robust, interactive app experiences. Responsibilities include:

- Translating responsive web and app designs from various tools (ex. Sketch, Zeplin, Invision, Figma) to React
- Working with various API's and external data sources
- Updating the internal builder to use the latest in React 16.8
- Developing both touchscreen TV and iPad applications using Electron and Cordova as frameworks.
- Utilizing web sockets to facilitate an iPad remote to TV application setup.
- Creating a reusable packaged component library using Storybook to share across apps.
- On-boarding new team members and creating a standardized guide for set up.
- Continually adding to the internal wiki with process guides, troubleshooting articles and helpful tips.

RED ACADEMY COMMUNITY PROJECT – MARCH 2018

Worked with a design and development team to build out a functional, responsive custom Wordpress website in a reduced time frame using PHP and javascript for a local improv company. Gained experience working with the Wordpress REST API and the Eventbrite API.

NORTHERN LIGHTS - KEYHOLDER - FEBRUARY 2017 - JANUARY 2018

Key holder and lead salesperson at a busy storefront. Worked closely with customers and a team of employees to ensure everyone left with the correct information and best experience.

SHELL SHOCK - SUPERVISOR/SOCIAL MEDIA - JANUARY 2015 - OCTOBER 2016

Supervisor of the downtown location. Responsibilities included opening and closing the store, handling busy situations without assistance, training other employees and running multiple social media accounts through Hootsuite.

FREELANCE WEB DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT - JUNE 2014 - JANUARY 2015

Independent web design and development jobs for clients, ranging from simple graphic design through to designing and creating an entire functional, compatible website using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

TEAVANA - TEAM LEADER - NOVEMBER 2011 - JANUARY 2014

Sales associate and manager on duty at Teavana. Consistently hit over 100% on sales targets and made the top 10 of North American sales multiple times. Responsibilities included opening and closing the store, cash handling, selling high end tea to customers, and leading a team of partners.

VOLUNTEER FOR WEST VANCOUVER MS WALK - 2006 - 2010

Set-up, tear down and general assistance during the annual MS walk in West Vancouver.

Technical Skills

Front end: JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, React Native, Vue, jQuery, HTML, and CSS3/SASS. Back end: Node.js, PHP, ExpressJS, GraphQL, PostgresQL, SQL, MongoDB, and Python. Other: Wordpress, Gulp, Webpack, GIT, Styled Components, Electron, Apache Cordova for iOS.

Education

RED Academy – Full Stack Development Diploma - 2018 University of Alberta – Undergraduate studies in Computer Science - 2012-2014 West Vancouver Secondary School – Academic/Highlander Honour Roll - 2008-2012

Skills

Great organization and communication skills with experience working in leadership roles in teams as well as individually.

Familiar in many aspects of social media and online ventures.

Personal interest in photography and videography. Have had work displayed in a gallery. Self-taught in classical guitar, piano, and vocals.